How long I stood there for, I do not know.
This was so different from everything I had imagined.
I remembered other travellers telling tales about London. Bright colourful tales of a grand wealthy city full of possibilities, full of travellers like me.
They had made it sound so exciting, so dreamy, so welcoming.
Not this cold, loud, busy place where I clearly didn’t belong.
I looked at the birds around me. The crows, the blackbirds, the pigeons, the magpies… they were at home here, in a world of black and white.
My green feathers made me feel so alien, I could feel everyone looking at me.
The shame made my heart race: I felt so scruffy after the flight, if only I could find a place to wash?
But that big wide river looked so wild, so grey, it was as terrifying as the rest.
For a moment, I thought of turning back.
I toyed with that idea. Wouldn’t it be nice to see the sun again, to see my mom, my friends?
But I didn’t have the strength. Not yet.
And what would I tell them? I would have to make up a story, a good story, maybe that’s what the other travellers did too.
The grey pavement lay bare in front of me. Not a blade of grass. Not a leaf. Not a sign of life. Only waste left by the humans.
I picked up a plastic straw. It felt strange in my beak. Strange, but strangely familiar.
I examined it closely.
With a bit of imagination, it could look like a twig.
With a bit of imagination, maybe one could use it to build a nest.
Not the kind of nest I had imagined, of course, probably a bit smaller.
But with a bit of imagination, and with time, maybe one day that nest could look like home.